Paul Muldoon papers, 1939-2010
Emory University
- Promotional material/Readings/Appearances, 1973-2005, Series 5; Boxes 38-41, 99-106 and OP 149-160, 173-174
  - Readings and appearances, 1980-2005, Subseries 5.3; Boxes 40-41, 101-106 and OP 174
    - New Jersey Unit's 2004 Record-a-thon, April 19, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 39)
    - Princeton University, Translating the Classics, April 23, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 40)
    - The University of Montana, Lucile Speer Memorial Lecture, April 26, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 41)
    - Rosenbach Museum & Library, 26 Lectures, 26 Poets, April 28, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 42)
    - Delaware Valley Poetry Festival, April 30, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 43)
    - Cafè-Auditori, Duets de Poesia, May 6, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 44)
    - Festival of Irish Arts and Culture, May 12, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 45)
    - Princeton Friends School, Frolic for Friends, May 22, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 46)
    - Princeton University, Ireland: A Literary Landscape, June 4-17, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 47)
    - Carlow Arts Festival, June 13, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 48)
    - Irish Writers' Centre, An Evening with Paul Muldoon, June 15, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 49)
    - Berlin PoesieFestival, June 27, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 50)
    - Poems From a Noisy Room: The Work of Paul Muldoon's, August 3, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - The Amy Clampitt Poetry Series, August 20, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - A Literary Evening to Benefit Pennsylvania Victory, September 11, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Scríobh, Literary Festival, September 19, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Paul Muldoon, Yusef Komunyakaa, and Gerald Stern, Reading and Signing, September 23, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - The 10th Geraldine R. Dodge Poetry Festival, September 30, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Poetry of Society of America, The Irish on the Americans, October 12, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - The Inauguration of the Eighth President of the University of Pennsylvania, October 14, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - The Council of the Grolier Club, Robert L. Nikirk Lecture, October 18, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - American Conference for Irish Studies Mid-Atlantic Regional Conference, "De-Provincializing Irish Studies," October 22-23, 2004 (Box OP174)
    - New Jersey Literary Hall of Fame, October 24, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - University of Michigan, Poetry Reading, October 28, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - University of Aberdeen, Writers Festival, November 5, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - The Sixteenth Aldeburgh Poetry Festival, November 7, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 13)
    - Chicago Humanities Festival: Readings, Performances, Lectures, Discussions, Films and Concerts, November 12, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 14)
    - City Arts & Lectures, Inc., 24th Annual Literary Events, November 15, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 15)
    - The Philadelphia Classical Society, Fall Professionals Day, November 20, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 16)
    - Johns Hopkins University, Writing Seminars Readings, December 1, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 17)
    - Princeton University, Death, Love, Liberty and The American Ballad: A Celebration in Words and Music, December 2, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 18)
    - Yale University, St. Anthony Hall, December 6, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 19)
    - Institut D'Anglais Charles V, "The End of the Poem: 'Dover Beach' by Matthew Arnold," December 13, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 20)
    - Princeton University, Tsunami Benefit Concert, January 8, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 21)
    - Aspen Writers' Conference, Winter Words, January 15, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 22)
    - Home of Elisa and Richard Rosen, The Poetry of Paul Muldoon, February 5, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 23)
    - Undated
    - Arts Council Shop: Poetry Reading, no date (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Arts Garage Poetry Reading, Hopewell, NJ, November 13 (no year given) (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - "Exoterica: Poetry at the Poor Month," An Beal Bocht Café, Riverdale, Bronx, NY, no date (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Festival Internacional de Poesia De LA Ciudad De Mexico, no date (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - The Glasgow Endowment Committee Sponsoring a Reading for Paul Muldoon, no date (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Irish Studies Program of Villanova University in conjunction with Chestnut Hill College, presents a poetry reading by Paul Muldoon, no date (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - New England Poetry Club: A Festival of Irish Poetry, no date (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Poets and Performers at the Murphy Center, NY: "Island Poets" with Paul Muldoon and Derek Walcott, introduced by Joseph Brodsky, no date (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Poetry and Politics in Ireland and Indiana, A Symposium, no date (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - University Bookshop Ltd., McMordie Hall, Student's Union, Queen's University, Belfast: Evening of Poetry with Richard Murphy and Paul Muldoon, no date (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - World Music, at the Blackfriars Arts Centre, Boston, Lincolnshire, no date (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Writer's Harvest: the National Reading, no date (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - A Writers Community: Interviews with Princeton-area Authors, no date (Box 106, Folder 24)
    - The Oxford Union, no date (Box 106, Folder 25)
    - Set Lists for Poetry Readings, no date (Box 106, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous readings, no date or place specified (Box 41, Folder 32)
- Business and personal papers, 1973-2010, Series 6; Boxes 42-43, 107-109
  The series consists of the business and personal papers of Muldoon from 1973-2010. It is comprised mostly of royalty statements from publishers, and pay slips from the BBC and academic institutions. Various drafts of Muldoon's curriculum vitae are also included, as are personal bank and pension fund statements. Royalty statements and contracts have been included below unless attached to other correspondence, in which case they are filed under that correspondent's name.
  Organized into two subseries: (6.1) Royalty statements and contracts and (6.2) Personal papers.
  - Royalty statements and contracts, 1980-2004, Subseries 6.1; Boxes 42, 107-108
    This subseries consists of statements, contracts, and receipts from Muldoon's publishing agreements from 1980-2004. In addition to publishing agreements, this subseries includes receipts from Muldoon's newspaper submissions and other receipts related to Muldoon's business affairs and travels.
    - British Broadcasting Company royalty statements, 1985-1995 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - British Broadcasting Company royalty statements, 1996-2004 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Contracts, 1995-2004 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Ecco Press royalty statements, 1987-1994 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Ecco Press royalty statements and contracts, 1997-1999 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - ECS Publishing statements, 1997-2003 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1972-1974 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1975-1979 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1980-1983 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1984-1986 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1993 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1995 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1996 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1997-1998 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 1999-2000 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 2001-2002 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, 2003-2004 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Faber royalty statements and contracts, no date (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Farrar, Straus and Giroux royalty statements and contracts, 1990-1993 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Farrar, Straus and Giroux royalty statements and contracts, 1995-2004 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Gallery Press, 1993-1994 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Gallery Press, 1995-2004 (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper submission receipts (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Oxford University Press statements and contracts, 1997-2004 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Receipts and invoices, 1979-2004 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - University of Oxford receipts, 1999-2004 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Personal papers, 1973-2010, Subseries 6.2; Boxes 43, 109
    This subseries consists of the personal papers of Paul Muldoon from 1973-2010. It includes travel itineraries, airplane tickets, appointment books, nametags, passports, and several editions of his curriculum vitae.
    - Airplane tickets and stubs, 1996-2010 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Champion Champ recipe, 1998 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Committee memberships, 1999-2004 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Concert set lists, 2003-2004 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Curriculum vitae--various editions with supplemental reviews and poetry (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - IMPAC Dublin Literary Award, 1998 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship application (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - List of invited contributors, 2001 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Literary Encyclopedia, 2004 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Nametags and cards, 1996-2003 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper remittance slips (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - The Open University, honorary degree, 2001 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Passports, 1973-1983 (Box 109, Folder 10)
    - Personal appointment books, 1986-1989 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Personal appointment books, 1990-1994 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Personal appointment books, 1995-2000 (Box 109, Folder 11)
    - Personal appointment books, 2001-2004 (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Princeton Junior School; miscellaneous materials (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Schedules and itineraries, 1996-2004 (Box 109, Folder 13)
- Photographs, circa 1950s-2004, Series 7; Boxes 44-45, 110 and OP 161-162, 175
  The series consists of photographs of Paul Muldoon from the 1950s-2004. Included are photographs of Paul Muldoon alone, with family members, family members alone, Paul Muldoon with others, and others alone. Where there is confirmation of a date, it is noted. The series includes a number of series of promotional shots of Paul Muldoon, as well as a substantial number of family photographs and photos with authors such as Seamus Heaney, Peter Fallon, Michael Longley and their families.
  Arranged by subject.
  - Paul Muldoon
  - Various shots of Muldoon as a boy and young man (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Portrait shot of Muldoon as a young man (Box OP161)
  - Various shots of Muldoon as an adult (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - A series of black and white portrait shots of Muldoon in front of foliage (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - A series of color portrait shots of Muldoon (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - A series of portrait shots of Muldoon taken outside (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Paul Muldoon at Poetry International, 1990. Photographs taken by David Hunter (postcard included) (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Promotional shots of Muldoon by Sigrid Estrada for The Annals of Chile, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Portrait sheets of Muldoon by Sigrid Estrada, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Promotional shots of Muldoon by Faber and Faber (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Promotional shots of Muldoon by Caroline Forbes (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - A series of black and white portrait shots of Muldoon taken by Jean Hanff Korelitz (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Promotional shots of Muldoon by Jean Hanff Korelitz (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Promotional shot of Muldoon by Niall; McDiarmid for Faber and Faber [image 0784-001.tif] (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Three shots of Muldoon reading (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Promotional shots of Muldoon by Sterling Zumbrunn, November, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of a painting of Muldoon by Shawcross, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Pen and ink drawing by Joolz, Manchester, 1984 (Box 44, Folder 16a)
  - Portrait shot of Muldoon sitting at typewriter, George Newson, 1984. (Box OP162)
  - Paul Muldoon at nine months old, circa 1952 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Paul Muldoon as a youth, circa 1950s (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Paul Muldoon as a youth, aged approximately 3 or 4, circa 1950s (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Paul Muldoon at British Broadcasting Corporation Belfast office, 1980 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Paul Muldoon at a portrait sitting in Gloucestershire, June 19, 1996, painting by Peter Edwards, unidentified photographer (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Paul Muldoon at the T.S. Eliot Prize ceremony, 1999, photographed by Susan Greenhill (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Muldoon at the 2001 Griffin Prize ceremony, June 7, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Muldoon at Honorary Doctoral Degree ceremony, Queen's University Belfast, July 4, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Muldoon at Honorary Doctoral Degree ceremony, University of Ulster, July 9, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Paul Muldoon at night, 2002, photograph possibly taken by Warren Zevon (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Paul Muldoon with family members
  - Various shots of Muldoon with siblings (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Various shots of Muldoon with parents and other family members (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Paul Muldoon with Jean Hanff Korelitz in Ireland (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Various shots of Muldoon and Jean Hanff Korelitz on U.S. trip (developed, September, 1987) (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Various shots of Muldoon and Jean Hanff Korelitz in Ireland (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Various shots of Muldoon and Jean Hanff Korelitz (with unidentified others) in U.S. (developed, August, 1988) (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Various shots of Muldoon and Jean Hanff Korelitz (with unidentified others) in U.S. (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Muldoon and Dorothy Muldoon (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon, Jean Hanff Korelitz and Peter Fallon, December 1, 1996 (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon with Jean Hanff Korelitz, Michael Longley and others, circa 1998 (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Paul Muldoon with Jean Hanff Korelitz, Seamus Heaney, Peter Fallon and others, circa 2000 (Box 110, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon and Asher Muldoon, May 14, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 14)
  - Paul Muldoon and Asher Muldoon, 2004 (Box 110, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon, Jean Hanff Korelitz and others, Middlebury College Honorary Degree ceremony, April, 2004 (Box 110, Folder 16)
  - Family members
  - Mother (various shots) (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Father (in color; various shots) (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - Mother and Father (various shots) (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Family (various shots) (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Dorothy Muldoon (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - Jean Hanff Koreltiz (various shots) (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Jean Hanff Korelitz and the Judith E. Wilson Poetry Workshop, Cambridge University, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Jean Hanff Korelitz, Michel Longley, Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, and others (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Jean Hanff Korelitz and unidentified other (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Jean Hanff Korelitz and unidentified others on a boat (various shots) (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Jean Hanff Korelitz and Asher Muldoon, May 14, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 17)
  - Paul Muldoon and others
  - Paul Muldoon, Yehuda Amichai and other unidentified others on a trip to Mexico? (various shots) (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Paul Muldoon, Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill and unidentified others in a group shot (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Paul Muldoon, Michael Longley (various shots) (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Paul Muldoon, Michael and Edna Longley, and unidentified others (various shots) (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Paul Muldoon with Michael Longley and unidentified others (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Paul Muldoon and the Lumbank Class of 1983, including Michael Longley (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Paul Muldoon, George Newson, Fred Burton and unidentified other, (holograph letter included, April 14, 1991) (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Paul Muldoon and unidentified others; photographs from Theo Jennissen from Poetry International, Rotterdam, 1990 (holograph letter included, August 8, 1990) (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Paul Muldoon with unidentified man at window (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Paul Muldoon with unidentified man and woman (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Paul Muldoon with unidentified man and woman standing (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Shots of Paul Muldoon with two unidentified men (same reel of film) (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Paul Muldoon and unidentified woman in tea shop (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Paul Muldoon and unidentified woman (two snap shots) (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Paul Muldoon, and Muldoon with others (teaching seminar) (Box 45, Folder 19a)
  - Paul Muldoon and Pat; Campbell in altar clothes, circa 1960s (Box 110, Folder 18)
  - Paul Muldoon with Lester Conner, March 1984 (Box 110, Folder 19)
  - Paul Muldoon with members of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, May 15, 1996, photographed by Mary Groskinsky (Box OP175)
  - Paul Muldoon, Seamus Heaney, and others, circa 1996 (Box 110, Folder 20)
  - Paul Muldoon, Catherine Carter and others, Adelaide, Australia, circa 1996 (Box 110, Folder 21)
  - Paul Muldoon, Toni Morrison and Daron Hagen, May 1999 (Box 110, Folder 22)
  - Paul Muldoon with W.S. Merwin, Derek Walcott and others, Ted Hughes memorial, October 1999, photographed by Nancy Crampton (Box 110, Folder 23)
  - Paul Muldoon and Peter Fallon, circa 1999 (Box 110, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon and Seamus Heaney, 2000-2001 (Box 110, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon and others, Honorary Doctoral Degree Ceremony, The Open University, Newcastle, April 2001 (Box 110, Folder 26)
  - Paul Muldoon with unidentified woman at the T.S. Eliot Prize ceremony, June 7, 2001, photographed by Susan Greenhill (Box 110, Folder 27)
  - Paul Muldoon and others, Honorary Doctoral Degree Ceremony, Queen's University Belfast, July 4, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 28)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon with others, Honorary Doctoral Degree Ceremony, University of Ulster, July 9, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 29)
  - Paul Muldoon and unidentified man, Griffin Prize ceremony, October 19, 2001 (Box 110, Folder 30)
  - Paul Muldoon and Tom Paulin, Hertford College, Oxfod, October 31, 2001, photograph by Norman McBeath (Box 110, Folder 31)
  - Paul Muldoon, Michael Longley, unidentified other, 2001, photographed by Susan Greenhill (Box 110, Folder 32)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon and others, related to the Oxford Professorship of Poetry, circa 2001 (Box 110, Folder 33)
  - Paul Muldoon and Seamus Heaney, Derek Walcott and others, celebration of Joseph Brodksy's posthumous publication, Nativity Poems, 2003 (Box 110, Folder 34)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon with Christopher Reeve and others, Middlebury college Honorary Degree Ceremony, April 2004 (Box 110, Folder 35)
  - Paul Muldoon and Peter Fallon, no date (Box 110, Folder 36)
  - Paul Muldoon and unidentified woman, no date (Box 110, Folder 37)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon and Michael Longley, no date (Box 110, Folder 38)
  - Photographs of Paul Muldoon and Mary McAleese, no date, photographed by Colm; Henry (Box 110, Folder 39)
  - Paul Muldoon and Kenneth Koch, no date (Box 110, Folder 40)
  - Paul Muldoon and Ben Kiely, no date, photographed by Colm; Henry (Box 110, Folder 41)
  - Paul Muldoon with Lavinia Greenlaw and Michael Hoffman, IMPAC Joyce Museum, no date, photographed by Colm Henry (Box 110, Folder 42)
  - Others and Negatives
  - Francesc Parcerias (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Mary Farl Powers (various shots) (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Portrait shots of two unidentified women (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Party event with unidentified others (various shots) (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Rachel Giese photographs with holograph letter (May 5, 1988) (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Seamus Heaney and family, Nobel Prize in Literature award ceremony, 1995 (Box 110, Folder 43)
  - Joseph Brodsky and unidentified youth, no date (Box 110, Folder 44)
  - Daughters of Peter Fallon, unidentified, no date (Box 110, Folder 45)
  - Unidentified cast of Vera of Las Vegas, photographs from undated performance (Box 110, Folder 46)
  - Madoc Hotel (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - Slides for The Annals of Chile book cover design (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - Negatives of Muldoon with family, and family without Muldoon (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Undeveloped negatives, Donegal (fading) (Box 45, Folder 28)
  - Undeveloped negatives (1) (Box 45, Folder 29)
  - Undeveloped negatives (2) (Box 45, Folder 30)
- Audiovisual material, 1987-2004, Series 8; Box 46
  The series contains audio and video recordings relating to the work of Paul Muldoon.
  Arranged by format.
  - Audio reel: Seamus Deane reviewing Muldoon, Why Brownlee Left (Box 46)
  - Audiotape: Leonard Lopate Show, "Please Explain: How to Read a Poem," featuring Muldoon and Molly Peacock, WNYC, recorded December 3, 2004 (Box 46)
  - Audiotape: Review of Latest Book of Poems (Box 46)
  - Compact Disc: Edward T. Cone, commercial recording of chamber compositions, including "New Weather," set to four poems by Paul Muldoon (Box 46)
  - Compact disc: various artists, "The Rose & The Briar: unequalized recording, July 26 2004 [soundtrack to book of essays on American music edited by Greil Marcus, "Blackwatertown" written by Paul Muldoon and performed by The Handsome Family] (Box 46)
  - Compact disc: radio recording related to the 2004 Shakespeare Prize, awarded to Paul Muldoon in Hamburg, Germany (Box 46)
  - Videotape: "Omnibus--Squeezing the Frog," BBC, August 13, 1987 (Box 46)